# NORMAN KEVIN DRIOTTZ

## MECHATRONIC ENGINEER

Email: nkdriottz@gmail.com

Address: Vicente Guerrero 1323 Col. Independencia

**Phone:** +52 (760) 9964-597 **Date of birth:** Jun 19,1995

Nationality: Mexican

Link: driottz.github.io/index.html

#### **OBJECTIVE**

 Dedicated and results-oriented mechatronic engineer with 4 years of experience in field. Possess practical skills in process simulation and modeling, technical drawing development, and automated manufacturing systems. Problem solver and team player with keen attention to detail and excellent command of mechanical and electronical engineering concepts

# **SKILLS & ABILITIES**

- Teamwork
- Problem-Solving
- Public speaking
- Motivator
- Fast learner

- Passionate
- Hard worker
- Eye for detail
- Open minded

## **EXPERIENCE**

# 2021-2022 Quality and Design Engineer, DAS NORTH AMERICA / HYUNDAI

- · Created performance requirements and quality standards for new engineering projects
- Participated in departmental meetings and made detailed presentations whenever necessary
- Collaborated with a team of 5 other design engineers in the installation and testing of new updated manufacturing lines
- · Applied specialized tools such as AutoCAD, SolidWorks and CATIA to develop concepts, fixtures and jigs
- Demonstrated excellence in technical troubleshooting, repair and testing manufacturing equipment malfunctions related to SPC (Statistical Process Control) issues

# 2018-2020 Project Engineer, Rheem

- · Used engineering concepts and manufacturing line manuals to ensure product quality and efficient running of all factory machinery
- Effectively communicated the scopes, schedules and budgets with both customers and contractors on a variety of projects
- · Conducted in-depth research for feasible ideas and trends in developing energy/time-efficient production lines
- · Managed delivery of end-to-end projects

### 2018 Design Engineer, Engineering Labor Metal

- · Applied specialized tools such as AutoCAD, SolidWorks and CATIA to develop concepts, tools, fixtures and jigs
- Interacted with customers and clients to establish tooling needs, brainstorm creative solutions and promote ongoing relationships
- Created 3D sketches using AutoCAD, Creo Parametrics, Solidworks.
  Programed tooling equipment and 3D printers to produce physical prototypes.

## **EDUCATION**

#### 2013-2018 Mechatronic Engineer, Mexicali B.C, U.A.B.C.

- Multiple places in robot making contests in categories such like, mini sumobot, automation robots and fighting robots
- 2nd place as CEO of a 3D printer manufacturing Company of an entrepreneur contest on the division of technology innovations.

## **CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES**

- Associate Mechanical Design Certification Dassault Systemes
- CENEVAL Satisfactory Test Approval

#### **LANGUAGES**

- English Advanced TOEFL
- Japanese Basic N5
- **German** Elementary
- Spanish Native